Guide to the Yale University Library Photographs and Memorabilia of Collections and Events
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Library photographs and memorabilia of collections and events
1925-1963
RU 387
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.75
The collection consists of photographic negatives of new acquisitions, specifically acquisitions for the Rare Book Room (now the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library). Also included are photographs of exhibits, library staff at work, various library operations and departments, and bookplates, as well as a commemorative edition of the Yale Daily News featuring the opening of Sterling Memorial Library..
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-A (YRG 32-A), Central records of the Yale University Library and records of the librarian.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by library department and by medium and in subsequent accessions.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of photographic negatives of new acquisitions, specifically acquisitions for the Rare Book Room (now the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library). Also included are photographs of exhibits, library staff at work, various library operations and departments, and bookplates, as well as a commemorative edition of the Yale Daily News featuring the opening of Sterling Memorial Library.
Academic libraries; Bookplates; Photographs; Yale University. Library -- Exhibitions; Yale University. Library
- Photographs and memorabilia of Yale University Library collections and events, 1925-1963; Series I
  - General
    - Bindings (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bookplates (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Gifts (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Coe Collection of Western Americana (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Map Collection (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Numismatics (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rare Book Room (Manuscripts and Archives and Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library)
    - Yale charter (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Letters
      - Henry Clay (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Daniel Defoe (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Nathan Hale (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Abraham Lincoln (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Ezra Stiles (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Isaac Watts (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Magazine covers and articles (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Maps (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Music (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Objects & memorabilia (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Portraits (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Paintings
    - Shaw, Bernard (busts) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Texts (Box 2, Folder 15 - 18)
    - War posters & propaganda (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Exhibits
    - Bursary system (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Getting a scholarship and a job (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Opportunities in various fields (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The residential colleges (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Joseph Conrad (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Gertrude Stein (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Libraries
    - 1742 Library (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Beinecke Library
      - Moving books (general), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - Moving, 1963 August 26-28 (Box 4, Folder 29 - 31)
      - Interior, Circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 32 - 33)
    - Linonia & Brothers (catalog records) (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Projects
    - Boswell Papers
      - Moving the collection to Sterling Library (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Copies of manuscript pages (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Benjamin Franklin Papers (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Library Services
    - Business Office (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Public Services (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Circulation (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Photographic Services (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Reference (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Technical Services
      - Cataloguing (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Preparations (Box 4, Folder 42)
      - Shipping & receiving (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Dedication & moving books, circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Librarians at work (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Library staff association (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Parties and gatherings (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Photographs from the film Making a Library (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Users and visitors (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - General (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Conservation Studio, Preservation Department, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 51 - 52)
  - Artistic rendition of Sterling Memorial Library entering the digital world, 1966 (Folder 6, Folder 53)
- Yale Daily News commemorative edition featuring opening of Sterling Memorial Library, 1931; Accession 19ND-A-476
  - Yale Daily News commemorative edition featuring opening of Sterling Memorial Library, 1931 April 11 (Box 1)
- Certificate awarded to Johanni Johnson, undated; Accession 19ND-A-498
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Certificate awarded to Johanni Johnson, undated (Box 1)